Dallas Smythe fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Dallas Smythe fonds
1913 - 1999
F-16
Q99982247
7.26 m of textual records 3 video cassettes 3 audio cassettes 54 photographs
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
LANGUAGES Most of the material in this fonds is in English. Some records are written in French, Spanish, German, Chinese, or Serbo-Croatian. PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION: 46 photographs located in F-16-4-0-5 PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION: 7 photographs located in F-16-6-2-1
Smythe, Dallas
Dallas Walker Smythe (1907-1992) was an economist and civil servant for the United States government, and a university professor in the field of communications in the United States and Canada.
He was born in Regina, Saskatchewan in 1907 and moved to California with his family in 1918. Smythe attended the University of California, Berkeley, where he received an A.B. (Economics) in 1928 and a Ph.D. (Economics) in 1937. His career as an economist began in 1934, when, at the College of Agriculture at the University of California, Berkeley, he worked as an Extension Specialist in Agriculture preparing studies of economic outlooks for various California farm products.
He left Berkeley in 1937 for Washington, D.C. to become a civil servant with the federal government. He worked as an economist with the Central Statistical Board, specializing in the coordination and review of agricultural information from various government agencies. In 1938, he joined the Wage and Hour Division of the Department of Labor as their senior economist. While at this Division, Smythe was responsible for preparing and presenting interpretive studies on the applicability of the Fair Labor Standards Act to a variety of industries, including textile mills, newspapers, railways, and lumber companies. Smythe left the Division in 1942 to become the principal economist, Division of Statistical Standards, Bureau of the Budget. He left that position in 1943 to join the Federal Communications Commission. As their chief economist, Smythe testified at FCC hearings and produced a number of statistical studies and reports on subjects such as radio frequency allocation and the public responsibilities of broadcasters. Throughout his career as a civil servant, Smythe belonged to pacifist or left-wing organizations, which later led to accusations of subversive conduct and disloyalty to the American government.
Smythe left the civil service in 1948 to join the faculty of the newly-formed Institute of Communications Research at the University of Illinois. In addition to lecturing on general economics, he taught the first course in the United States on the political economy of communications. The primary focus of his research was television, including its content, effects on family life, and portrayal of reality. He also studied the mass media and its influence on public opinion. With the development of satellite communication, he studied the effects of this new technology on international communications.
Partly because of his pacifist political beliefs, Smythe left the United States in 1963 to become the first Chairman of the Social Sciences Division at the Regina Campus of the University of Saskatchewan. When he reached the mandatory retirement age in 1973, he left Regina to serve as visiting professor of communications at the University of California, San Diego. He joined the faculty of Simon Fraser University in 1974, serving as the first chairman of the Department of Communications Studies. While Smythe continued to write on mass media, regulating the radio spectrum, and communications theory, he also produced Dependency Road: Communications, Capitalism, Consciousness and Canada, his study of the domination of Canadian communications by American influences and its effects on consciousness.
Smythe became professor emeritus at Simon Fraser University in 1980. Following a brief period at Temple University in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, he returned to teach at SFU until 1986. He accepted short-term appointments at Ohio State University and the University of Hawaii before retiring in 1988. He was working on his autobiography and a book about the theory of communications when he died in 1992.
Smythe married twice and had five children. He and his first wife Beatrice had three children: Sandra (born 1937), Susan (born 1938), and Roger (born 1943). Smythe later married Jennie Newsome Pitts, and the couple had two children: Patrick (born 1954), and Carol (born 1961).
published
Full
Published
Title of the fonds is based on the name of the records creator.
The fonds consists of records arising from Smythe's activities with the University of California, Berkeley; the U.S. Central Statistical Board; the U.S. Department of Labor (Wage and Hour Division); the U.S. Federal Communications Commission; his academic work; and from his various personal activities. Fonds includes correspondence, teaching materials, publications, research materials, reports, written testimony, reference material, and other records.
Original order was maintained by the archivist where possible. Where no order was apparent, the materials were arranged by the archivist.
Photographic materials; Sound recordings; Moving images; Textual records; Communications; Government
The fonds was donated by Patrick Smythe, son of Dallas Smythe, in two accessions.
All accessions have been processed as of September 2002. No further accruals are expected.
For related records, please see the Dallas W. Smythe collection / Thomas H. Guback (collector), F-41.
Series descriptions and file lists are available.
- Personal records, 1915 - 1999; F-16-1; 1.13 m of textual records 3 audiocassettes 3 videocassettes
  published
  Series consists of Smythe's personal records arising from his various activities, such as his employment as a faculty member at several universities; his studies at the University of California, Berkeley; his involvement with the United States military; his private business venture in the television industry; his ongoing research into various areas of personal interest; his travels to China and Europe; and his work on his autobiography. Series also contains personal records of Smythe's wife, Jennie, and of his father, J.W. Smyth. Series includes correspondence, contracts, annual reports, legal records, reports, notes, drafts, research papers, diaries, newsletters, published articles, and a curriculum vitae.
  - Faculty employment, 1942 - 1984; F-16-1-1; 38 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of Smythe's personal records arising from his employment as a faculty member at the University of Illinois; the Regina campus of the University of Saskatchewan; the University of California, San Diego; Simon Fraser University; and Temple University. Subseries includes correspondence, contracts, reports, legal records, and other materials. Materials relate to sabbatical leaves, Smythe's lawsuit against Simon Fraser University regarding research leave, and allegations of un-American activities delaying Smythe's appointment at the University of Illinois.
    - Illinois appointment - loyalty struggle, 1942 - 1965; F-16-1-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 16-1)
      Textual records
      Open
    - University of Illinois annual reports, 1950 - 1984; F-16-1-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 16-1)
    - University of Illinois appointment, 1948 - 1963; F-16-1-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 16-1)
    - European sabbatical notes, 1959 - 1960; F-16-1-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 16-1)
    - Regina job, 1962 - 1963; F-16-1-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 16-1)
    - University of Saskatchewan, 1963 - 1973; F-16-1-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 16-1)
    - Reorganization, University of Saskatchewan at Regina, 1968 - 1974; F-16-1-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 16-1)
    - Sabbatical correspondence, 1971; F-16-1-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 16-1)
    - 1971-1972 Arrangements for sabbatical, F-16-1-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 16-2)
    - University of California, San Diego appointment correspondence, 1970 - 1973; F-16-1-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 16-2)
    - SFU Political Science, Sociology, Anthropology correspondence, 1969 - 1974; F-16-1-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 16-2)
    - Political Science, Sociology, Anthropology dispute, 1/2, 1971 - 1975; F-16-1-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 16-2)
    - Political Science, Sociology, Anthropology dispute, 2/2, 1971 - 1975; F-16-1-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 16-2)
    - SFU Department of Communications, 1975 - 1980; F-16-1-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 16-2)
    - Australia - Murdoch (University interchange), 1976 - 1977; F-16-1-1-0-15 (Archival box - standard 16-2)
    - SFU appointment, 1974 - 1982; F-16-1-1-0-16 (Archival box - standard 16-3)
    - SFU lawsuit correspondence, 1980; F-16-1-1-0-17 (Archival box - standard 16-3)
    - Smythe vs. Simon Fraser University, 1982; F-16-1-1-0-18 (Archival box - standard 16-3)
    - Smythe vs. Simon Fraser University, 1975 - 1980; F-16-1-1-0-19 (Archival box - standard 16-3)
    - Smythe vs. Simon Fraser University, 1974 - 1982; F-16-1-1-0-20 (Archival box - standard 16-3)
    - Temple - apartment and appointment, 1980; F-16-1-1-0-21 (Archival box - standard 16-3)
  - Course notes, 1921 - 1944; F-16-1-2; 20 cm of textual records; Smythe's Ph.D. dissertation is located in series F-16-6 (Publications and presentations).
    Subseries consists of records arising from Smythe's activities as a student at the University of California, Berkeley. Subseries includes class notes, term papers, and research notes.
    - Economics, F-16-1-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 16-4)
    - Dissertation research, 1921; F-16-1-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 16-4)
    - Term papers, 1925 - 1926; F-16-1-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 16-4)
    - Course notes (various classes), 1928 - 1930; F-16-1-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 16-4)
    - Course notes and exams, 1928 - 1930; F-16-1-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 16-4)
    - Economics 1/2, 1929; F-16-1-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 16-4)
    - Economics 2/2, 1929; F-16-1-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 16-4)
    - Report on Davenport, 1930; F-16-1-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 16-4)
    - Marketing, 1930 - 1931; F-16-1-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 16-4)
    - Economics 1/2, 1930 - 1931; F-16-1-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 16-5)
    - Economics 2/2, 1930 - 1931; F-16-1-2-0-11 (Archival box - standard 16-5)
    - Public utilities, 1931; F-16-1-2-0-12 (Archival box - standard 16-5)
    - Overhead costs, 1933; F-16-1-2-0-13 (Archival box - standard 16-5)
    - Dissertation, 1936; F-16-1-2-0-14 (Archival box - standard 16-5)
    - Dissertation, 1937; F-16-1-2-0-15 (Archival box - standard 16-5)
    - Dissertation correspondence and notes, 1936 - 1944; F-16-1-2-0-16 (Archival box - standard 16-5)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1931; F-16-1-2-0-17 (Archival box - standard 16-5)
  - Family papers, 1915 - 1963; F-16-1-3; 5 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of miscellaneous records of various members of the Smythe family. Records of Dallas Smythe include a 1915 diary, military records, and records arising from a private business venture to establish a television station in the Champaign-Urbana area in Illinois. Subseries also includes employment and pension records of Smythe's father, J.W. Smyth, and issues of Alternatives, a newsletter edited by Dallas Smythe's wife Jennie.
    - Diary and pressed flowers, 1915 - 1916; F-16-1-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 16-5)
    - "My Heart Belongs to Daddy" (story by Smythe), 1939; F-16-1-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 16-5)
    - Military papers (also Phi Beta Kappa certificate), 1932 - 1948; F-16-1-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 16-5)
    - J.W. Smyth (father's) pension records, 1942 - 1948; F-16-1-3-0-4 (Archival box - standard 16-5)
    - Alternatives newsletter, 1961 - 1963; F-16-1-3-0-5 (Archival box - standard 16-5)
    - Champaign - Urbana television station project, 1952 - 1954; F-16-1-3-0-6 (Archival box - standard 16-5)
  - Subject files, 1938 - 1992; F-16-1-4; 28 cm of textual records 3 audiocassettes 3 video cassettes
    Subseries consists of records arising from Smythe's personal interests and activities. Subseries includes lectures by Smythe and his colleague Tran Van Dinh (on audiocassette); interviews with Smythe (on video cassette); correspondence and reports regarding Smythe's FBI file and the Dies Committee on Subversive Activities (the House Committee on Un-American Activities); drafts and correspondence arising from proposed radio and movie projects developed by Smythe; correspondence regarding a festschrift of his work; and records relating to his anti-war activities.
    - Committees of correspondence, 1961 - 1963; F-16-1-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 16-6)
    - Dies Committee 1/2, 1938 - 1954; F-16-1-4-0-2 (Archival box - standard 16-6)
    - Dies Committee 2/2, 1938 - 1954; F-16-1-4-0-3 (Archival box - standard 16-6)
    - FBI report - copy annotated by Smythe 1/2, 1982; F-16-1-4-0-4 (Archival box - standard 16-6)
    - FBI report - copy annotated by Smythe 2/2, 1982; F-16-1-4-0-5 (Archival box - standard 16-6)
    - FBI report - correspondence, 1978 - 1982; F-16-1-4-0-6 (Archival box - standard 16-6)
    - Festschrift correspondence, 1991; F-16-1-4-0-7 (Archival box - standard 16-6)
    - Institute of Communications Research anniversary, 1988; F-16-1-4-0-8 (Archival box - standard 16-7)
    - Interview, 1984; F-16-1-4-0-9 (Archival box - standard 16-7)
    - Limericks, F-16-1-4-0-10 (Archival box - standard 16-7)
    - Movie - Electronic Tiger, 1983 - 1984; F-16-1-4-0-11 (Archival box - standard 16-7)
    - Movie - Electronic Tiger 1/2, 1984 - 1985; F-16-1-4-0-12 (Archival box - standard 16-7)
    - Movie - Electronic Tiger 2/2, 1984 - 1985; F-16-1-4-0-13 (Archival box - standard 16-7)
    - Personal security file (copied from U. of Illinois), 1948; F-16-1-4-0-14 (Archival box - standard 16-7)
    - The Public program (Smythe's proposed TV program), 1948; F-16-1-4-0-15 (Archival box - standard 16-7)
    - Regina War Immigrant Fund, 1967 - 1970; F-16-1-4-0-16 (Archival box - standard 16-7)
    - UDC (plans for an unnamed organization), 1982; F-16-1-4-0-17 (Archival box - standard 16-7)
    - Vancouver CCF (Canada-China Friendship Association), 1978 - 1980; F-16-1-4-0-18 (Archival box - standard 16-7)
    - Veterans Against Nuclear Arms 1/2, 1985 - 1992; F-16-1-4-0-19 (Archival box - standard 16-8)
    - Veterans Against Nuclear Arms 2/2, 1985 - 1992; F-16-1-4-0-20 (Archival box - standard 16-8)
    - Half a century of work (a video cassette summary of Dallas Smythe's career), 1985; F-16-1-4-0-21 (Archival box - small 16-60)
    - Canada: communications and control; Information power: communication and domination (video cassette interviews with Dallas Smythe), 1987; F-16-1-4-0-22 (Archival box - small 16-60)
    - "Roundtable" (videotape of Dallas Smythe and others discussing privatization), 1987; F-16-1-4-0-23 (Archival box - small 16-60)
    - Tran Van Dinh lecture at the University of California, San Diego, 1974; F-16-1-4-0-24 (Archival box - small 16-60)
    - Dallas Smythe seminar on a theory of communications, at the Centre for International Research on Communications and Information Technology (CIRCIT), 1989; F-16-1-4-0-25 (Archival box - small 16-60)
    - Dallas Smythe lecture on a theory of communications at Northwestern University at Evanston, 1991; F-16-1-4-0-26 (Archival box - small 16-60)
  - Travel diaries, 1971 - 1989; F-16-1-5; 12 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of travel diaries written by Dallas and Jennie Smythe during their travels to China, England and Hungary.
    - China - Dallas Smythe, 1971; F-16-1-5-0-1 (Archival box - standard 16-8)
    - China - Jennie Smythe (3 volumes), 1971; F-16-1-5-0-2 (Archival box - standard 16-8)
    - England - Dallas Smythe, 1972; F-16-1-5-0-3 (Archival box - standard 16-8)
    - Hungary - Dallas Smythe, 1972; F-16-1-5-0-4 (Archival box - standard 16-8)
    - Hungary - Jennie Smythe (2 volumes), 1972; F-16-1-5-0-5 (Archival box - standard 16-8)
    - Europe - Dallas Smythe, 1973; F-16-1-5-0-6 (Archival box - standard 16-8)
    - China - Dallas Smythe, 1979; F-16-1-5-0-7 (Archival box - standard 16-9)
    - Australia - Dallas Smythe, 1989; F-16-1-5-0-8 (Archival box - standard 16-9)
  - Biographical material, 1936 - 1999; F-16-1-6; 10 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of records arising from Smythe's compilation of his autobiography. Included is Smythe's curriculum vitae, correspondence with colleague Thomas Guback and others, drafts of two chapters of the autobiography, and newspaper clippings and articles regarding Smythe.
    - Counterclockwise, 1936 - 1965; F-16-1-6-0-1 (Archival box - standard 16-9)
    - Counterclockwise, 1963 - 1984; F-16-1-6-0-2 (Archival box - standard 16-9)
    - Counterclockwise, 1965 - 1967; F-16-1-6-0-3 (Archival box - standard 16-9)
    - Resumes and list of publications, 1948 - 1975; F-16-1-6-0-4 (Archival box - standard 16-9)
    - Lists of publications, 1948 - 1992; F-16-1-6-0-5 (Archival box - standard 16-9)
    - Source material and correspondence with T. Guback, 1958 - 1992; F-16-1-6-0-6 (Archival box - standard 16-9)
    - Counterclockwise - chapter 4, "Mature Immaturity: The Urbana years, 1948-1963", [ca 1990] - [ca 1999]; F-16-1-6-0-7 (Archival box - standard 16-9)
    - Counterclockwise - chapter 5, "Immature Maturity: Washington, 1937-1938", [ca 1990] - [ca 1999]; F-16-1-6-0-8 (Archival box - standard 16-9)
    - Clippings and articles, 1938 - 1992; F-16-1-6-0-9 (Archival box - standard 16-9)
- Correspondence, 1943 - 1992; F-16-2; 1.38 m of textual records
  Series consists of Smythe's correspondence with family members and colleagues. Series includes incoming letters and copies of outgoing letters.
  - Chronological correspondence, 1943 - 1992; F-16-2-1; 1.26 m of textual records
    Subseries consists of correspondence arranged chronologically. Subseries includes incoming letters and copies of outgoing letters.
    - Correspondence 1/2, 1943 - 1949; F-16-2-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 16-10)
    - Correspondence 2/2, 1943 - 1949; F-16-2-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 16-10)
    - Correspondence, 1969 - 1970; F-16-2-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 16-10)
    - Correspondence, 1970 - 1971; F-16-2-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 16-10)
    - Correspondence, 1972; F-16-2-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 16-10)
    - Correspondence, 1972 - 1973; F-16-2-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 16-10)
    - Correspondence, 1973; F-16-2-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 16-11)
    - Correspondence, 1973 - 1974; F-16-2-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 16-11)
    - Correspondence, 1974; F-16-2-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 16-11)
    - Correspondence, 1974; F-16-2-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 16-11)
    - Correspondence, 1974; F-16-2-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 16-11)
    - Correspondence, 1974 - 1975; F-16-2-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 16-11)
    - Correspondence, 1975; F-16-2-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 16-11)
    - Correspondence, 1975 - 1976; F-16-2-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 16-11)
    - Correspondence, 1975 - 1976; F-16-2-1-0-15 (Archival box - standard 16-12)
    - Correspondence, 1976 - 1977; F-16-2-1-0-16 (Archival box - standard 16-12)
    - Correspondence, 1977; F-16-2-1-0-17 (Archival box - standard 16-12)
    - Correspondence, 1977; F-16-2-1-0-18 (Archival box - standard 16-12)
    - Correspondence, 1977 - 1978; F-16-2-1-0-19 (Archival box - standard 16-12)
    - Correspondence, 1977 - 1978; F-16-2-1-0-20 (Archival box - standard 16-13)
    - Correspondence 1/2, 1978 - 1979; F-16-2-1-0-21 (Archival box - standard 16-13)
    - Correspondence 2/2, 1978 - 1979; F-16-2-1-0-22 (Archival box - standard 16-13)
    - Correspondence, 1978 - 1979; F-16-2-1-0-23 (Archival box - standard 16-13)
    - Correspondence, 1979 - 1980; F-16-2-1-0-24 (Archival box - standard 16-13)
    - Correspondence 1/2, 1979 - 1980; F-16-2-1-0-25 (Archival box - standard 16-14)
    - Correspondence 2/2, 1979 - 1980; F-16-2-1-0-26 (Archival box - standard 16-14)
    - Correspondence 1/2, 1980; F-16-2-1-0-27 (Archival box - standard 16-14)
    - Correspondence 2/2, 1980; F-16-2-1-0-28 (Archival box - standard 16-14)
    - Correspondence, 1981; F-16-2-1-0-29 (Archival box - standard 16-14)
    - Correspondence, 1981; F-16-2-1-0-30 (Archival box - standard 16-14)
    - Correspondence, 1981; F-16-2-1-0-31 (Archival box - standard 16-15)
    - Correspondence, 1981 - 1982; F-16-2-1-0-32 (Archival box - standard 16-15)
    - Correspondence 1/2, 1982 - 1983; F-16-2-1-0-33 (Archival box - standard 16-15)
    - Correspondence 2/2, 1982 - 1983; F-16-2-1-0-34 (Archival box - standard 16-15)
    - Correspondence 1/2, 1983; F-16-2-1-0-35 (Archival box - standard 16-15)
    - Correspondence 2/2, 1983; F-16-2-1-0-36 (Archival box - standard 16-16)
    - Correspondence 1/2, 1983 - 1984; F-16-2-1-0-37 (Archival box - standard 16-16)
    - Correspondence 2/2, 1983 - 1984; F-16-2-1-0-38 (Archival box - standard 16-16)
    - Correspondence 1/2, 1984 - 1985; F-16-2-1-0-39 (Archival box - standard 16-16)
    - Correspondence 2/2, 1984 - 1985; F-16-2-1-0-40 (Archival box - standard 16-16)
    - Correspondence 1/2, 1985; F-16-2-1-0-41 (Archival box - standard 16-16)
    - Correspondence 2/2, 1985; F-16-2-1-0-42 (Archival box - standard 16-17)
    - Correspondence 1/2, 1985 - 1986; F-16-2-1-0-43 (Archival box - standard 16-17)
    - Correspondence 2/2, 1985 - 1986; F-16-2-1-0-44 (Archival box - standard 16-17)
    - Correspondence 1/2, 1986 - 1987; F-16-2-1-0-45 (Archival box - standard 16-17)
    - Correspondence 2/2, 1986 - 1987; F-16-2-1-0-46 (Archival box - standard 16-17)
    - Correspondence, 1986 - 1987; F-16-2-1-0-47 (Archival box - standard 16-17)
    - Correspondence 1/2, 1987; F-16-2-1-0-48 (Archival box - standard 16-18)
    - Correspondence 2/2, 1987; F-16-2-1-0-49 (Archival box - standard 16-18)
    - Correspondence 1/2, 1988; F-16-2-1-0-50 (Archival box - standard 16-18)
    - Correspondence 2/2, 1988; F-16-2-1-0-51 (Archival box - standard 16-18)
    - Correspondence, 1988; F-16-2-1-0-52 (Archival box - standard 16-18)
    - Correspondence, 1989; F-16-2-1-0-53 (Archival box - standard 16-19)
    - Correspondence 1/2, 1989; F-16-2-1-0-54 (Archival box - standard 16-19)
    - Correspondence 2/2, 1989; F-16-2-1-0-55 (Archival box - standard 16-19)
    - Correspondence 1/2, 1990; F-16-2-1-0-56 (Archival box - standard 16-19)
    - Correspondence 2/2, 1990; F-16-2-1-0-57 (Archival box - standard 16-19)
    - Correspondence, 1991; F-16-2-1-0-58 (Archival box - standard 16-19)
    - Correspondence, 1991 - 1992; F-16-2-1-0-59 (Archival box - standard 16-19)
  - Nominal correspondence, 1974 - 1992; F-16-2-2; 13 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of correspondence arranged by name of correspondent. Subseries includes incoming letters and copies of outgoing letters.
    - Letters between friends (mostly Tran van Dinh), 1974 - 1983; F-16-2-2-0-1 (Archival box - small 16-20)
    - Ping Ferry (W.H. Ferry), 1990 - 1992; F-16-2-2-0-2 (Archival box - small 16-20)
    - George Gerbner, 1991; F-16-2-2-0-3 (Archival box - small 16-20)
    - Stephen Griew, 1978 - 1983; F-16-2-2-0-4 (Archival box - small 16-20)
    - Sue Curry Jensen, 1982 - 1985; F-16-2-2-0-5 (Archival box - small 16-20)
    - John Hochheimer, 1991 - 1992; F-16-2-2-0-6 (Archival box - small 16-20)
    - E. DeSilva (E. Silva) - University of Toronto, 1989 - 1992; F-16-2-2-0-7 (Archival box - small 16-20)
- Agricultural economics, 1934 - 1938; F-16-3; 12 cm of textual records